You'd better make a run for it now.
You'll never clear up this misunderstanding.
D-Don't run off, damn you!
I only came to pay back
the fight that was sold to me.
Celty-san, please take Young Miss somewhere safe.
I'm counting on you, Shooter!
It all began with a cell phone.
The Apple Doesn't Fall Far From the Tree
Probably, my family was more...
well-off than others, I think.
People have said to me,
"You grew up wanting for nothing, didn't you?"
My father, my mother, my grandfather
were all really kind-hearted...
I see, I see.
The cell phone was given to me
for security purposes.
My father was against it,
saying I was still too young, but...
At first, I never went on the internet.
And then, right around that time...
I witnessed someone getting bullied.
"Bullying is wrong."
That's what I said, without thinking.
Oh... yes. I was scared.
That I might be the next one to get picked on.
But...
Nothing happened.
The bullying stopped,
and I didn't get bullied, either.
Everyone understood.
That's what I thought at the time.
Everyone's always smiling, having fun...
how wonderful life is, I thought.
I decided I wanted to become someone
who could make even more people smile.
Since I thought at the time
that my father was in the business of selling art...
I thought I'd become an artist,
create beautiful paintings that would make people smile,
and have my father sell them...
Oh, I'm sorry. My cell phone, right?
Not long after that,
I accidentally left my cell phone at a friend's house...
You don't have to tell me!
I always do whatever Akane-chan tells me to!
The other girls don't do anything
to displease the young lady either, do they?
No, they don't.
The Awakusus are
really frightening people, all right?
If you have a fight and injure her,
there's no telling what trouble they'd pin on you!
The girl's father and mother came over right away
to return my cell phone.
Pardon us for causing any trouble...
Thank you for being so considerate.
And that's what made me think
something wasn't quite right...
What? Well, they didn't have to go out of their way
to bring it over when we'd see each other at school.
No, no, it was no trouble at all.
Uh... um...
Awakusu
Awakusu Group
Yakuza
...running a gallery as a front.
Big Boss Dogen Awakusu
That's when I came to realize.
What our family business really was.
Everyone was saying,
"Let's bully Akane-chan next."
And they told me if I bullied you with them,
then they'd stop bullying me.
But... then one of the girls...
She said that your father was really scary,
so we shouldn't make you mad...
Everybody was afraid of me.
Everyone at school, everyone's family,
everyone... they were all lying.
They were all just pretending to be happy.
Akane! Dinnertime!
I had dinner as usual.
That day it was just my mother and me.
Well? Is it good?
I don't remember what we talked about,
but it was probably about school, as usual.
What? Hmm... I'm not sure,
but I thought I should just act like nothing had happened.
Homework, homework...
But...
Akane! What's wrong? Akane!
My mother and father seemed to know instantly
that I'd realized what our family business was.
Thank you for the meal.
Especially with my father... somehow...
So...
I thought if I went someplace
where nobody knew me or the Awakusu name,
Running away from home
something might change.
And then, on a certain messageboard...
Name: Nakura
Akane-chan,
I understand how you feel
I learned a lot from that person.
Although I was a little bit scared...
Hello.
You're Akane-chan, right?
Nice to meet you, I'm Nakura.
When I met that person, she was a pretty lady,
so nice, and so smart.
After that, I met with her often
and told her my story.
His name is Izaya.
I thought he could help you out
in all kinds of ways.
Yes, she introduced me to Izaya-san.
Before I knew it,
I'd told them everything about my family.
I did think that I'd messed up.
Like, what if they got scared of me? But...
Izaya-san said this to me,
"It's all right. I'm not scared.
Well, that would be a lie. But you're you, Akane-chan."
One month later, I ran away from home.
I spent the night at manga cafés and diners.
Izaya-san gave me lots of pointers
on how to succeed at running away.
"Do you hate your grandpa and your dad?"
Izaya-san asked me that once.
I don't know.
That's how I answered him.
Then he told me that I should
think it over carefully until I did know.
But...
"There's no guarantee that
they'll both be safe until then."
He said he was worried because my grandfather and father
were both feared by so many people.
"The person in the photo
is the scariest hit man in all of Ikebukuro,
and he might be targeting
your grandfather and father," he said.
That man's name...
He said it was Heiwajima Shizuo.
If we go on like this,
we'll attract too much attention, huh?
Jeez, what a pest!
Ah, so your comrades
were done in by Shizuo...?
But I wonder why he was with Akane-chan.
Who knows? That's what I'd like to know.
By the way, what kind of condition were the bodies in?
Oh, uh, just out of personal interest...
Now this isn't Shizuo's handiwork.
Is that your opinion as a doctor?
No, rather, as his longtime friend.
These bodies are in too good shape.
If it were him, he wouldn't have stopped there.
Shiki-san, you know that
well enough yourself, don't you?
That may be true, but who else
could kill our guys with his bare hands...?
Escaping Criminal Caught
on Security Camera...
Serial Murderer in Ikebukuro
Hijiribe
Oh, so it's you.
What's up, all of a sudden?
I thought we were done talking this morning.
Or could it be that
you miss the sound of my voice?
If so, that's far too heavy a load for me.
I don't have time to listen to your inane jokes.
What did you say to Mikado?
What are you talking about?
It was you who jacked my handle, wasn't it?
Where's your proof?
No one but you would do something like that.
What did you say to Mikado?
Why do you think that
I said anything to Mikado-kun?
Even if I did assume your name,
it doesn't necessarily mean
that I talked to Tanaka Taro-kun, right?
If someone named Orihara Izaya
was to assume my name and pull some stunt,
I can't think of any other purpose.
Let's say you're right.
What are you going to do about it?
Answer the question!
I wish I had the time.
Don't you know that
something's happening in Ikebukuro right now?
What are you talking about?
Now that's what you should ask him...
Mikado-kun himself.
That's right, just tell him to his face.
"That wasn't me yesterday.
It was Orihara Izaya."
Easy enough, right?
Since you and Mikado-kun are best friends.
Cut it out.
No matter what you think,
that's how Mikado-kun sees you, apparently.
Seriously, he's too trusting.
He's beyond salvation!
And that's why he's so noble.
Like a sacrificial lamb.
I said, cut it out!
I'm not fond of getting yelled at.
You bastard.
Emergency!
In Ikebukuro, Toramaru
are attacking Dollars!!
You out for revenge on behalf of the guys
who got wasted by Shizuo and me?
That wasn't the Dollars. I did that myself.
About that, we were the ones at fault,
so I got no beef with you.
Sure, I thought it was overkill,
so I did call out that guy Heiwajima Shizuo.
Oh, so Shizuo did that to you?
So anyway, we've buried the hatchet
on that incident.
But do you know
what you Dollars did in Saitama?
If it was just our team that got taken out,
I could live with it.
But taking out guys who just happened to be there?
No way was I gonna keep quiet about that.
So what do you want with me?
You're like one of the faces of the Dollars, right?
Who the hell is your boss?
I see, so that's your move...
The hell if I know.
Huh?
I said I don't know
who the hell the boss of the Dollars is.
Don't play clueless with me.
There's no way you don't know.
You know how there are hordes of locusts?
Huh?
You think those locusts
know who their leader is?
Same with schools of fish.
Although I guess ants and bees have their queens.
It's the same kind of thing.
And besides, if one of your guys
gets offed by some foreigner,
everyone from that country
starts to look like the enemy... isn't it like that?
What you guys are doing?
The Dollars are mostly made up of guys
who are there because they want to be, right?
Then it's just like a sports team or a club.
When someone in an athletic club causes a scandal,
the whole team takes the rap. Happens all the time.
Anyone calling himself a member of the Dollars
without that possibility in mind is just a moron, right?
Right.
Huh?
Well, speaking for myself,
I am prepared to face the music in that case.
But this clueless bunch going rogue on us?
I just can't bring myself to laugh at them
for getting what they deserve.
What are you trying to say?
That I'll be happy to take you on
in this fight of yours.
Too conspicuous here.
Let's go somewhere else.
Raira Academy Field No. 2
Kabaddi, kabaddi, kabaddi, kabaddi...
Who knew such a place existed
smack in the middle of Ikebukuro...
Don't you want to put that thing
you're carrying to use?
Isn't it a shortened bokuto or something?
Oh, right. So you noticed it.
You're injured. I'll give you a handicap.
Right back atcha.
Why don't I lend you this, old man?
Hey, I'm not even 25 yet. Brat!
Jeez, talk about crashing the party!
Oh, we got this.
These guys are total wimps, huh?
Anyway, that Mikado-senpai dude's a real wuss,
don't you think?
Did that guy really start the Dollars?
Aoba better not be messing with us!
If he is, I'll kill him! And I'll take his girl, too!
Did Aoba have a girlfriend?
You know, those twins!
I'll kill him! I'm gonna kill him now!
How did these guys find us here?
Don't tell me it was Orihara Izaya...
"Just now, Kadota-san of the Dollars started walking
towards the back of Field No. 2 at Raira!"
He was with some scary-looking dude,
but it could be that he's with the guys
who are attacking the Dollars right now."
"I don't think Kadota-san would lose any fight,
but I'm still worried..."
This guy is the leader of Toramaru...
Could one of you go to Field No. 2
and see what's going on?
Okay, I will.
Hey, hey, you stealing that thing?
Well, this one's got the keys in the ignition!
Hold up. Get off.
Huh? You're not the type to say
that stealing's bad, right?
Black...
The bikes that the Toramaru guys rode up on
are out front. Take one of those!
What's your problem all of a sudden?
I'm gonna try to reel in this thread.
Not that I know how far it goes...
Can't just have the Dollars getting routed, can we?
Finding that flea bastard with these binoculars...
Well, that's not happening, is it?
I came here because I thought it would be harder for him
to make a move with so many witnesses around...
Doesn't look like I can stay here for long.
He might have already been
at the office, or where Tom-san is.
And Shinra's apartment, and Kasuka's place...
Damn!
For God's sake, what's with today?
Huh?
Kadota? And is that the dude from the other day?
From: Nakura
Subject: Important Information!
I feel like hurling...
It's all right.
I'm on your side, Akane-chan,
so no worries.
Big Sister, you're a good person?
Huh?
Oh, right. I guess a headless horse
is a graphic sight for a child...
Huh?
Oh, Shooter! Are you feeling depressed?
Don't worry, this horse is very gentle.
R-Right. You know, he's like one of those superheroes
that can switch their faces!
And right now, he happens to be
changing to a brand-new face...
Really?
Yes, really.
And stay away from the Dollars for a while.
It's not the Dollars spinning out of control
that you're afraid of, right?
Isn't it the thought of being left behind
by the ever-transforming Dollars?
So what I want is for you
to become the leader of the Blue Square.
What am I supposed to do...?
Look! There's his new face!
No way... S-Sorry, Celty-san!
There's somewhere I need to be right now,
so I'll be leaving!
And sorry, Sonohara-san! I don't think I can go
with you today, so you should probably head home.
Also, if you hear from Aoba-kun,
whatever you do, don't answer, okay?
Somebody just came out.
It's the boy the Black Bike was escorting.
He does seem to be working solo...
Is that building the Black Bike's hideout?
Too soon to make that assumption.
What should we do about that punk?
The boy's true identity warrants investigation.
I will follow that boy.
Sloan, I ask that you stay here and continue tracking
the Black Bike and the girl with the glasses.
Please understand.
I understand. You can leave this to me.
I wonder what's going on?
Uh... um... What happened, exactly?
"The biker gang that's attacking
the Dollars right now is called Toramaru,
and I just spotted one of their leader's girlfriends
eating in Ikebukuro.
I don't have the guts to kidnap her,
so anyone who's up to it, give it a go!
It's the girl sitting
second from the left in the photo..."
Wait, I've seen this girl somewhere...
Oh... Kamichika-san? They're being ordered
to kidnap Kamichika-san's friend?
Celty-san...
I'll be going now, too!
Those people from yesterday
might attack again. So be careful.
Right. Uh... um... Thank you very much.
Akane-chan, this lady is a good person,
so wait for me without any worries, okay?
Okay.
Varona, the girl with the glasses just ran off, too.
Looks like she's going after the punk.
And the Black Bike?
No sign of that one.
Understood. I shall pursue both the boy and the girl.
Like catching two stools in one fall.
There's no such phrase.
Besides, there's no telling what kind of punk that kid is.
Affirmative. As an opponent, he is worthy.
You seem to be enjoying yourself, Varona.
Let's suppose that boy is another aberration.
In my eyes, nothing would be more welcome.
Next Time
on Durarara!! x2
No Use Crying Over Spilt Milk
What are the Dollars, anyway?
Can't describe it in a word.
I only just joined myself.
Even if you're one of them, it's not obvious.
It's way too late to tell you now.
Next time: No Use Crying Over Spilt Milk.